<resources>
    <string name="app_name">IYANA</string>
    <string name="welcome_message"><b>Welcome to IYANA</b></string>
    <string name="nav_about">About</string>
    <string name="nav_help">Help</string>
    <string name="nav_mood_graphs">Mood Charts</string>
    <string name="nav_time_graphs">Time Charts</string>
    <string name="nav_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="nav_enter_data">Enter Data</string>
    <string name="settings_title">Settings</string>
    <string name="settings_help">You can enter up to 10 factors that you want to track every day. Mood will be tracked in any case - no need to enter that one. You should choose factors that you think might have an influence on your mood or be influenced by your mood.\n\nThe factors should be trackable by entering values from good to bad (++, +, +-, -, --).\n\nExamples are weather, sleep, sports, food, completed daily plan, meditation. You could also add menstruation if you think it might have an influence on your mood. In that case you could skip that question most of the days and only answer it when you get your period.\n\nWhen you edit factor names, you will be asked if the values that were already recorded for that factor should be deleted or if you want to keep them and only rename the factor.</string>
    <string name="settings_save">Save</string>
    <string name="settings_factor_hint">enter factor title</string>
    <string name="factor_storage_key">com.example.rakvat.IYANA.FACTOR_STORAGE_KEY</string>
    <string name="demo_mode_preference">com.example.rakvat.IYANA.DEMO_PREFERENCE_STORAGE_KEY</string>
    <string name="demo_mode_key">com.example.rakvat.IYANA.DEMO_PREFERENCE_KEY</string>
    <string name="enter_data_title">Enter Data</string>
    <string name="enter_data_help">Here you can enter your current mood and the other factors you wanted to track. You can add more factors or change them by going to Settings.\n\n++ means very good\n+ means good\n+- means neutral, neither good nor bad\n- means bad\n-- means very bad\n\nYou do not have to answer every row each time.\n\nIt might help to write down some notes with your definition for ++, +, +-, -, -- for mood and other factors. That way your answers can get more consistant.</string>
    <string name="enter_data_save">Save</string>
    <string name="settings_saved">Saved</string>
    <string name="data_saved">Saved</string>
    <string name="enter_data_note_label">Note (e.g. special events that influenced your mood)</string>
    <string name="enter_data_note">Note</string>
    <string name="enter_data_mood_label">Mood</string>
    <string name="time_chart_help">This chart shows your mood over time. It also shows the additional factors you are tracking. This allows you to watch mood changes over time and understand possible causes of mood changes by looking at patterns. Maybe you are in a bad mood one day after eating bad or one week before menstruation?\n\nOnce you have collected more than one week of data, you can move through the time by touching the chart and moving in horizontal direction.\n\nYou can read the notes you have taken when entering data by touching data points in the graph.</string>
    <string name="mood_chart_help">Here you can see how your mood is influenced by the factors you are tracking (or how your mood influences these factors). This is called correlation. There is one chart for each factor. You can navigate through them by swiping the left and right. The x-axis is always the mood and the y-axis the factor.\n\n These charts only show values of the last 30 days. Older values are fading to white. If there are multiple entries in the database with the same values, they are shown as stacks of squares.\n\nWhat does that tell you? Let\'s say you are tracking the factor sleep and looking at that chart. If the squares are distributed randomly over the whole chart, then there is probably no relation between your mood and your sleep. If you see most the squares close to a diagonal from the left bottom to the right top, you can conclude that your mood tends to be better when you slept well. However, it\'s also possible that you don\'t sleep well when you are in a bad mood. (It\'s also possible that you tend to enter a bad value for sleep if you are in a bad mood even though you slept well.) That\'s something the data can\'t tell you, but you might know or learn that yourself if you track and reflect your mood over time.</string>
    <string name="help"><b>Motivation for this App</b>\nYou are feeling sad, unhappy, unmotivated, depressed and don\'t know why? This app is a tool that could help you to better understand your mood and factors that lead to mood changes.\n\n<b>Disclaimer</b>\nIf you are experiencing acute severe depressions or other forms of mental distress that is preventing you to live your normal life, please find professional help. Call a friend, a crisis hotline, a doctor, psychologist or psychiatrist. Be careful with spiritual anti-crisis offers. People offering the often don\'t have profound training and you might need more than fairy tales and hanky-panky.\n\nRemember, you are not alone. Thousands of people go through these very bad moods and thousands of people are out there to help. IYANA is not meant to help in acute crisis but it can be one of your tools for preventing crisis.\n\n<b>Privacy</b>\nAll the data you enter in this app stays on your device. When uninstalling the app, all data will be deleted.\n\n<b>Bad Mood and Crisis Prevention</b>\nTo prevent phases of bad mood or crisis that keep you from being able to live the life you want to live, it is good to get to know your moods, feelings, needs, triggers and coping mechanisms better.\n\nThe About Section of this app has some more thoughts about the reasons behind bad moods and bad feelings. One good collection of resources about handling crisis is this page http://theicarusproject.net/welcome-to-the-crisis-toolkit/.\n\nOne basic advice to prevent crisis: Track your mood daily. You can use IYANA or some other tool for this purpose. Write down a crisis plan. It should list multiple levels of bad mood, describe you feel in each level so that you can identify, which level you are in, and list coping mechanismis for each level, that should help you to get back into better mood. Here is a very short example, just to give you an idea how such a plan could look like. Your plan should be waaaaay more detailed.\n++: Everything is good. ⇒ Keep going and enjoy.\n+: Ok, but not super happy. Troubling thoughts. ⇒ Meditate, cook.\n+-: Kind of bad. Unmotivated, can\'t concentrate. ⇒ Sports.\n-: Bad. Feeling depressed. ⇒ Meet friends, get rest.\n--: Very bad. Breakdown. Not able to do anything. ⇒ Take some time off, get professional help.\n\n<b>How This App can Help</b>\nNo matter if you have a crisis plan or if you simply want to take more control over your mood, IYANA can be one of your tools to better understand your mood, reasons for mood changes and thus give you the power to influence your mood. That way, you could be able have better time, enjoy and be motivated to get some things done.\n\n<b>A Tour through IYANA</b>\nWhen you first use this App, get started by reading the Help and About sections. If you want to get started with tracking your mood, go to the settings section and choose one to three factors you want to track. You can add more later, when you got a feeling for the app. After that, go to "Enter Data" and enter how you are doing at the moment. If you are doing this regularly over some days, there will soon be enough data get some insights from the time and mood charts.\n\nIn most sections of this app you can find a "?" in the top right corner. Clicking on that will give you more detailed information and help about that specific part of the app.\n\n<b>Load Demo Data</b>\nTo get a better feeling for what IYANA is doing, you can load some demo data here. Your own data won't be lost.\n</string>
    <!-- This is part of the help text -->
    <string name="home"><b>A Tour through IYANA</b>\nWhen you first use this App, get started by reading the Help and About sections. If you want to get started with tracking your mood, go to the settings section and choose one to three factors you want to track. You can add more later, when you got a feeling for the app. After that, go to "Enter Data" and enter how you are doing at the moment. If you are doing this regularly over some days, there will soon be enough data get some insights from the time and mood charts.\n\nIn most sections of this app you can find a "?" in the top right corner. Clicking on that will give you more detailed information and help about that specific part of the app.</string>
    <string name="about"><b>What does IYANA stand for?</b>\nIYANA is an abbreviation, the first part of the famous saying "If You Are Not Angry, you are not paying attention."\n\n<b>What does that have to do with a mood analysis app?</b>\nMost resources about well-being and mental health want you to simply be happy, let go of all the troubling thoughts and the anger. Some of them just want you to get back to normal so that you can become a "productive" part of the society again.\n\nThe mindset behind this app is different: \n1. It\'s ok to be angry. In fact, if you look at all the stuff happening in the world, how can you not be angry?\n2. It\'s not (only) your fault, if you are in a phase of bad mood or crisis. All the competition, injustice, isolation and exploitation inherent in the capitalistic world order, that is dominating our lives, is responsible not only for misery but also for an increase in depressions around the world (see e.g.http://nymag.com/scienceofus/2016/03/for-80-years-young-americans-have-been-getting-more-anxious-and-depressed.html).\n3. You don\'t need to get better to be more productive. If you want, you can try to get better to be able to enjoy more of your life, to do more of those things that you care about, and maybe, when feeling strong enough, even to make the world a little bit better.\n\n<b>A Better World?</b>\nIs there alternative? Is that even possible? You can find more thoughts about the transformation into societies with less pressure and less injustice and less mental issues here http://transform-social.org.</string>
    <string name="help_ok">Ok</string>
    <string name="data_mood_required">Please enter your mood.</string>
    <string name="nav_diary">Diary</string>
    <string name="diary_data_help">The Diary view allows you to show your data and notes of the past days. You can move through the data by pressing the buttons at the bottom of the list. It is also possible to edit and delete previous entries if you made a mistake and want to correct it.</string>
    <string name="edit">Edit</string>
    <string name="delete">Delete</string>
    <string name="entry_deleted">Entry Deleted</string>
    <string name="todo">todo</string>
    <string name="nav_back">Back</string>
    <string name="nav_forward">Forward</string>
    <string name="settings_confirm_delete">Delete Values</string>
    <string name="settings_confirm_rename">Rename Factors</string>
    <string name="settings_cancel">Cancel</string>
    <string name="settings_nothing_changed">Nothing Changed</string>
    <string name="settings_question_edited">You edited</string>
    <string name="settings_question_factor_names">factor name(s).</string>
    <string name="setting_question_delete_or_rename">Should the values of those factors be deleted or do you only want to rename the factors?</string>
    <string name="demo_data">Use Demo Data</string>
</resources>
